Regino Ballester Camús

Mallorca, Spain | LinkedIn

(+34) 653 196 524 reginoballester@gmail.com

Profile

Experienced Senior Frontend Software Developer with experience of more than 10 years in different companies related to tourism, insurance and e-commerce.

I have been working as a project manager in different teams, having to mediate with the entire business part and external providers, architecture... as well as analyzing, planning and managing the teams and their tasks in an agile environment.

Work Experience

eDreams Odigeo, Barcelona, Frontend Senior Software Engineer | July 2021 - Present

- Tech Stack: ReactJS, Cypress, Jest, Java, GraphQL, Vue, ES6, Backbone, Lodash, SASS, Figma, Lucid, Custom Design System, GIT, Docker, Mocha, Cucumber, Gherkins, Scrum/Kanban Agile Methodology, Jenkins
- Role:
 - Customer Service Area In charge of giving our customer better experience to avoid calls and implement all the different funnels (refund, schedule changes...) by web.
 - Collaborating with product, architecture, different teams/areas.
 - In charge of technical interviews and mentoring to new teammates, giving training about different projects or technologies.

Avoris Travel, Mallorca, Project Manager | Senior Software Engineer | October 2018 - July 2021

- Tech Stack: Angular, Jest, SpringBoot, Java, ES6, SASS, GIT, Openshift, Kibana, Mocha, Scrum Agile Methodology, Jenkins
- Role:
 - Senior Software Engineer: In charge to migrate all funnel flights with all integrations to different providers and other areas
 - **Project Manager (Flights** (B2C/B2B), **Customer Service** (B2C/B2B), **Electronic Signature**): Manage different developers team; coordinate with architecture, product, other teams and business stakeholders; maintenance and supervision of different applications; act as an interlocutor between external providers; develop functional analysis and technical designs; perform different scrum ceremonies.

TODO Patterson, Mallorca, Frontend Senior Software Engineer | May 2018 - October 2018

- o **Tech Stack:** Angular, ES6, BEM, Lodash,, SASS, GIT, Scrum Agile Methodology, Mercurial, Grunt, Gulp, Vagrant, Wordpress, Prestashop
- O Role:
 - Closed projects with clients like Camper, Meet Barcelo, Barcelo Hoteles and Grupo Pinero.
 - Web design and optimization / audits

Brújula (eDreams ODIGEO), Mallorca, Frontend Senior Software Engineer | April 2015 - April 2018

- Tech Stack: Backbone, Lodash, Underscore, JSP, Jasmin, Mocha, Angular, XML, Mercurial, Grunt, Cucumber, Selenium, Gherkins, Java, ES6, SASS, GIT, JQuery, Scrum Agile Methodology, Jenkins
- Role:
 - Dynpack product (Flight + Hotel), migration of the legacy platform to a new version.
 - New developments A/B to improve conversion.
 - Team leader for a year.

GFI (Movistar), Alicante, Frontend Software Engineer | January 2015 - March 2015

- o Tech Stack: Angular, Jasmin, Protractor, JPA, Vanilla, Scrum Agile Methodology, SVN
- Role:
 - After an initial formation of AngularJS, Jasmine, Protractor, I entered into a project for Telefónica.
 - Graphic components development (windows). Drivers, services, policies implementations as well as views. REST calls with the JPA part.

T-Systems (Allianz), Tarragona, COBOL Developer | May 2014 - January 2015

- Tech Stack: COBOL, CICS, JCL, DB2
- Role:
 - After a COBOL/CICS/JCL/DB2 formation I entered into a project of Allianz Seguros.
 - Using CICS o IBM RAD Developer I performed maintenance functions for all the claims part in Colombia, Portugal, Spain, Brazil and Phoenix. In this maintenance, new functionalities and analysis of batch chains - where JCLs and programs were debugged for their correct operation- were carried out.

Esportsale, Valencia, Software Engineer Ecommerce | April 2013 - April 2014

- Tech Stack: Magento, PHP, VanillaJS, MySQL, Shopify, SEO, SEM, Remarketing, BrightPearl, Mailchimp, AWS Amazon, Wordpress
- Role:
 - Modules and different integrations with Magento
 - Migration to Shopify with physical store system
 - Social media

Softonic, Barcelona, Internship Frontend Developer | Sep 2012 - Dec 2012

o Tech Stack: Vanilla, Hydra, Node, JQuery, HTML/HTML5, CSS/CSS3, SVN, Agile

Education

Graduate in Telematics

University of Valencia, ETSE \mid 2006 - 2010, Valencia, Spain